<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?><type interface="true" language="gradle" name="org.gradle.play.PlayApplicationSpec" version="3.0"><description> 
 Definition of a Play Framework software component that is built by Gradle. 
</description><method name="setInjectedRoutesGenerator" returnType="void"><description> 
 Configures the style of router to use with this application. 
 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 By default, a static routes generator is used to generate a singleton router.  This requires that all the actions 
 that the router invokes on the application's controllers are either Scala singleton objects, or Java static methods. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 In Play 2.4+, a injected routes generator is recommended.  This requires that the router declares its 
 dependencies to the application's controllers in its constructor.  The controllers methods need to be instance methods. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='param'&gt;param:&lt;/b&gt;injectedRoutesGenerator false if a static router should be generated (default). 
 true if an injected router should be generated. 
</description><parameter type="boolean" name="injectedRoutesGenerator"/></method><method name="getInjectedRoutesGenerator" returnType="boolean"><description> 
 Will an injected router be generated for this application? 
 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='return'&gt;returns:&lt;/b&gt;false if a static router will be generated for the application, 
 true if an injected router will be generated. 
</description></method><method name="platform" returnType="void" delegationTarget="org.gradle.play.platform.PlayPlatform"><description> 
 Specifies a &lt;a href='type://org.gradle.play.platform.PlayPlatform'&gt;org.gradle.play.platform.PlayPlatform&lt;/a&gt; with a given set of requirements that this 
 component should be built be for.  Can accept a map of play, scala and/or java requirements or a string 
 representation of the desired play platform. 
 &lt;pre&gt; 
     model { 
                  platform 'play-2.3.9' 
                  platform play: '2.3.2' 
                  platform play: '2.3.6', scala: '2.10' 
                  platform play: '2.3.7', scala: '2.11', java: '1.8' 
              } 
          } 
      } 
 &lt;/pre&gt; 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='param'&gt;param:&lt;/b&gt;platformRequirements Map of Play requirements or the name of an Play platform. 
</description><parameter type="java.lang.Object" name="platformRequirements"/></method><property name="injectedRoutesGenerator" type="boolean"><description> 
 Will an injected router be generated for this application? 
 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='return'&gt;returns:&lt;/b&gt;false if a static router will be generated for the application, 
 true if an injected router will be generated. 
</description></property></type>