<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<type interface="true" language="gradle" name="org.gradle.plugin.use.PluginDependenciesSpec" version="3.0">
    <description> 
 The DSL for declaring plugins to use in a script. 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 In a build script, the &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; script block API is of this type. 
 That is, you can use this API in the body of the plugins script block to declare plugins to be used for the script. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;h3&gt;Relationship with the apply() method&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 The &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; block serves a similar purpose to the &lt;a href='type://org.gradle.api.plugins.PluginAware#apply(java.util.Map)'&gt;org.gradle.api.plugins.PluginAware#apply(java.util.Map)&lt;/a&gt; method 
 that can be used to apply a plugin directly to a &lt;a href='type://Project'&gt;Project&lt;/a&gt; object or similar. 
 A key difference is that plugins applied via the &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; block are conceptually applied to the script, and by extension the script target. 
 At this time there is no observable practical difference between the two approaches with regard to the end result. 
 The &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; block is a new, incubating, Gradle feature that will evolve to offer benefits over the &lt;a href='type://apply()'&gt;apply()&lt;/a&gt; approach. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;h3&gt;Strict Syntax&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 The &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; block only allows a strict subset of the full build script programming language. 
 Only the API of this type can be used, and values must be literal (e.g. constant strings, not variables). 
 Moreover, the &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; block must be the first code of a build script. 
 There is one exception to this, in that the {}} block (used for declaring script dependencies) must precede it. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 This implies the following constraints: 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;ul&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Only &lt;a href='type://PluginDependenciesSpec#id(String)'&gt;#id(String)&lt;/a&gt; method calls may be top level statements&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='type://PluginDependenciesSpec#id(String)'&gt;#id(String)&lt;/a&gt; calls may only be followed by a &lt;a href='type://PluginDependencySpec#version(String)'&gt;PluginDependencySpec#version(String)&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href='type://PluginDependencySpec#apply(boolean)'&gt;PluginDependencySpec#apply(boolean)&lt;/a&gt; method call on the returned object&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='type://PluginDependenciesSpec#id(String)'&gt;#id(String)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='type://PluginDependencySpec#version(String)'&gt;PluginDependencySpec#version(String)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='type://PluginDependencySpec#apply(boolean)'&gt;PluginDependencySpec#apply(boolean)&lt;/a&gt; methods must be called with a literal argument (i.e. not a variable)&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; script block must follow any &lt;code&gt;buildscript {}&lt;/code&gt; script block, but must precede all other logic in the script&lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;/ul&gt; 
 &lt;h3&gt;Available Plugins&lt;/h3&gt; 
 &lt;h4&gt;Core Plugins&lt;/h4&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 Core Gradle plugins are able to be applied using the &lt;code&gt;plugins {}&lt;/code&gt; block. 
 Core plugins must be specified without a version number, and can have a &lt;i&gt;qualified&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;unqualified&lt;/i&gt; id. 
 That is, the &lt;a href='type://java'&gt;java&lt;/a&gt; plugin can be used via: 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;pre&gt; 
 plugins { 
   id 'java' 
 } 
 &lt;/pre&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 Or via: 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;pre&gt; 
 plugins { 
   id 'org.gradle.java' 
 } 
 &lt;/pre&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 Core Gradle plugins use the &lt;a href='type://org.gradle'&gt;org.gradle&lt;/a&gt; namespace. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 For the list of available core plugins for a particular Gradle version, please consult the User Guide. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;h4&gt;Community Plugins&lt;/h4&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 Non-core plugins are available from the &lt;a href="http://plugins.gradle.org"&gt;Gradle Plugin Portal&lt;/a&gt;. 
 These plugins are contributed by users of Gradle to extend Gradle's functionality. 
 Visit &lt;a href="http://plugins.gradle.org"&gt;plugins.gradle.org&lt;/a&gt; to browse the available plugins and versions. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 To use a community plugin, the fully qualified id must be specified along with a version. 
 &lt;/p&gt; 
</description>
    <method name="id" returnType="org.gradle.plugin.use.PluginDependencySpec" delegationTarget="apply" documented="true">
        <description> 
 Add a dependency on the plugin with the given id. 
 &lt;p&gt; 
 &lt;pre&gt; 
 plugins { 
     id "org.company.myplugin" 
 } 
 &lt;/pre&gt; 
 Further constraints (e.g. version number) can be specified by the methods of the return value. 
 &lt;pre&gt; 
 plugins { 
     id "org.company.myplugin" version "1.3" 
 } 
 &lt;/pre&gt; 
 
 Plugins are automatically applied to the current script by default. This can be disabled using the &lt;a href='type://apply false'&gt;apply false&lt;/a&gt; option: 
 
 &lt;pre&gt; 
 plugins { 
     id "org.company.myplugin" version "1.3" apply false 
 } 
 &lt;/pre&gt; 
 
 This is useful to reuse task classes from a plugin or to apply it to some other target than the current script. 
 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='param'&gt;param:&lt;/b&gt;id the id of the plugin to depend on 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='return'&gt;returns:&lt;/b&gt;a mutable plugin dependency specification that can be used to further refine the dependency 
</description>
        <parameter type="java.lang.String" name="id"/>
    </method>
</type>
