<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<type interface="true" language="gradle" name="org.gradle.tooling.BuildActionExecuter" version="3.0">
    <description> 
 Used to execute a &lt;a href='type://BuildAction'&gt;BuildAction&lt;/a&gt; in the build process. 
 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='param'&gt;param:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;T&gt; The type of result produced by this executer. 
 @since 1.8 
</description>
    <method name="run" returnType="T">
        <description> 
 Runs the action, blocking until its result is available. 
 
 @throws UnsupportedVersionException When the target Gradle version does not support build action execution. 
 @throws org.gradle.tooling.exceptions.UnsupportedOperationConfigurationException 
          When the target Gradle version does not support some requested configuration option. 
 @throws org.gradle.tooling.exceptions.UnsupportedBuildArgumentException When there is a problem with build arguments provided by &lt;a href='type://BuildActionExecuter#withArguments(String...)'&gt;#withArguments(String...)&lt;/a&gt;. 
 @throws BuildActionFailureException When the build action fails with an exception. 
 @throws BuildCancelledException When the operation was cancelled before it completed successfully. 
 @throws BuildException On some failure executing the Gradle build. 
 @throws GradleConnectionException On some other failure using the connection. 
 @throws IllegalStateException When the connection has been closed or is closing. 
 @since 1.8 
</description>
    </method>
    <method name="run" returnType="void">
        <description> 
 Starts executing the action, passing the result to the given handler when complete. This method returns immediately, and the result is later passed to the given handler's &lt;a href='type://ResultHandler#onComplete(Object)'&gt;ResultHandler#onComplete(Object)&lt;/a&gt; method. 
 
 &lt;p&gt;If the operation fails, the handler's &lt;a href='type://ResultHandler#onFailure(GradleConnectionException)'&gt;ResultHandler#onFailure(GradleConnectionException)&lt;/a&gt; method is called with the appropriate exception. See 
 &lt;a href='type://BuildActionExecuter#run()'&gt;#run()&lt;/a&gt; for a description of the various exceptions that the operation may fail with. 
 
 &lt;br&gt;&lt;b class='param'&gt;param:&lt;/b&gt;handler The handler to supply the result to. 
 @throws IllegalStateException When the connection has been closed or is closing. 
 @since 1.8 
</description>
        <parameter type="org.gradle.tooling.ResultHandler" name="handler"/>
    </method>
    <interface name="org.gradle.tooling.ConfigurableLauncher"/>
    <documentation/>
</type>
